Guide to the Darlington Autograph Files, 1610-1914 DAR.1925.07
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Darlington Autograph Files
1610-1914
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Darlington family
DAR.1925.07
3.17 Linear Feet (8 boxes, 6 oversize folders)
The Darlington Autograph Files contain an array of documents authored or signed by various historical figures between 1610 and 1914. Some of the documents are related to one another through specific historical events, while others were collected by the Darlington family for their rarity. The documents include correspondence, receipts, wills, warrants, depositions, indentures, land surveys, and speeches, among other forms of documentation. Many of the items are from such notable individuals as Benjamin Franklin, Napoleon Bonaparte, William Penn, Robert Fulton, Robert R. Livingston, King George III, and Patrick Henry. Prominent citizens of the Pittsburgh area are also represented in the collection, with letters and other documents from Mary Croghan Schenley, James O'Hara, William Wilkins, and Richard Butler. The collection is arranged in alphabetical order. Digital reproductions of the collection are available online.
Existence and Location of Copies
Digital reproductions of this collection are available online.
Scope and Content Notes
The Darlington Autograph Files comprise an array of documents authored or signed by various historical figures between 1610 and 1914. It consists of 601 documents, some related to one another through specific historical events while others were collected by the Darlington family for their rarity. The Darlington family had an interest in collecting and preserving the history of western Pennsylvania and purportedly amassed the largest private library west of the Allegheny Mountains.
This collection broadly displays the historical interests of William Darlington and his wife, Mary Carson O'Hara Darlington. The colonial period, French and Indian War, Revolutionary War, Whiskey Rebellion, westward expansion, and other topics were of particular interest to the family. Many of these items are clearly in the realm of interest of the Darlington family who collected rare books and manuscripts related to geography, literature, and the history of western Pennsylvania.
Many of the items are from such notable figures as Benjamin Franklin, Napoleon Bonaparte, William Penn, Robert Fulton, Robert R. Livingston, and Patrick Henry. Prominent citizens of the Pittsburgh area are also represented in the collection, with letters and other documents from Mary Croghan Schenley, James O'Hara, William Wilkins, Presley Neville, and Richard Butler, among others.
Some of the earliest items within the collection document the personal and business correspondence of the Penn family fromas early as 1641, including the division of land between Lord Baltimore and William Penn in 1685. Many of the assembled records describe events in western Pennsylvania. Letters and other items from George Croghan, a seventeenth century settler, fur trader, and Indian agent stationed at Fort Pitt, and his extended family are part of the collection. Among these items is a bill of sale to William Croghan, Jr. for four slaves. Later Croghan family letters include those between his infamous granddaughter, Mary Croghan Schenley, who eloped with the much older Captain Edward Schenley. Additionally, there are letters to Mary's father from Captain Schenley and others written during the time of the scandal, which garnered a worldwide audience in the early 1840s. Other items include letters from General Edward Braddock and Brigadier General Edward Hand written while he was stationed at Fort Pitt.
Many pieces in the collection are from renowned military and political figures of the eighteenth and nineteenth centuries. They include Thomas Jefferson, George Mason, Henry Knox, William McKinley, Jr., Alexander Hamilton, Arthur St. Clair, Andrew Jackson, Gouverner Morris, and Albert Gallatin among others. Foreign leaders represented in the collection are the Marquis de Lafayette, King George III, and Napoleon Bonaparte.
Quite a few of the documents' authors have backgrounds in artistic and scholarly professions. They include John Ormsby (1829-1895), a British translator known for his translation of Don Quixote de la Mancha; Henry Wickham Steed (1871-1956), a British journalist and historian; and famed British stage actor, Sir Henry Irving (1838-1905).
While most of the documents are original, a small number are photocopies, handwritten copies, typed transcripts, or other forms of surrogate records, all of which are noted as such. A number of the handwritten copies were made for business purposes at the time the original was created and, in some cases, years or decades later. These items are denoted by the bracketed term [duplicate]. Modern hand-written copies are denoted by the bracketed term [copy]. Additionally, some items have accompanying transcripts.
In some instances the year of an undated item may be known due to references to events in the document, as with some of the Croghan family letters, the date is indicated in brackets. Other information enclosed in brackets include comments about the item being described, such as the language in which it is written or, in one case, a note about an exceptional watermark. Many individuals represented in the collection had one or more military titles during their lifetime. However, in the contents list a military title is only used when the title and last name are the only types of identification used in a document. Although it is not documented in the inventory, occasionally a note, news clipping, or paper describing an event or person has been included with the item, presumably accumulated by library staff. Item level description is not provided, only the names of the correspondents, signatories, and dates are given.
A volume created by William Darlington, which contains letters and engraving of William Penn and his family, is found within the collection. Oversize materials are found in box 8; please note that they may be related to other materials of interest in the collection.
Arrangement
The Darlington Autograph Files are arranged alphabetically by the author's last name. In the instance that more than one piece of correspondence from an author exists, those letters have been arranged chronologically. If the document was created by a city, state, institution, and so on, and has no author, it is filed alphabetically under the name of the creator.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Part of the original donation of William M. Darlington's family library to the University of Pittsburgh in 1918 and 1925 by his daughters, Edith Darlington Ammon and Mary Carson Darlington.
Custodial History
This collection was located in the Darlington Memorial Library in the University's Cathedral of Learning until 2007 when it was moved to the ULS Archives Service Center for processing, storage, preservation and service. However, it remains in the custodianship of the ULS Special Collections Department.
Previous Citation
Darlington Autograph Files, 1610-1914, DAR.1925.07, Darlington Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Personal correspondence; Autographs (Manuscripts); United States -- History -- French and Indian War, 1755-1763; United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783; United States -- Territorial expansion; Pittsburgh (Pa.) -- History; Fort Pitt (Pa.); Pennsylvania -- History; Whiskey Rebellion, Pa., 1794; Legal correspondence; Commercial correspondence; Property records; Land surveys; Speeches; Politics; Government; Personal papers; George, King of Great Britain, III; Penn, William; Hand, Edward; Napoleon, Emperor of the French, I; Hamilton, Alexander; Jefferson, Thomas; Schenley, Mary Croghan; Croghan, George
- James Abercromby to William Denny, April 13, 1758 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Original account given by a Mohawk who came out of the French camp and handwritten transcription, September 11, 1684 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Messrs. Adair & Co., Overpayment notice, ca. 1777 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Dr. William Addison to William Croghan Jr., March 29, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Dr. William Addison to William Croghan Jr., September 16, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Ann Aitken to Mr. A. Ritchie, April 11, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- William and Margaret Allen, Indenture to Jeremiah Langhorn, March 7, 1738/9 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Jeffrey Amherst, 1st Baron Amherst to Colonel Bradstreet, July 29, 1759 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Jeffery Amherst, 1st Baron Amherst to Colonel Byrd, August 20, 1761 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Jeffery Amherst, 1st Baron Amherst to Sir William Johnson, August 22, 1762 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Jeffery Amherst, 1st Baron Amherst to Sir George Yonge, August 22, 1790 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- John Armstrong to Rebeckah Armstrong, June 21, 1779 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Benedict Arnold permit to pass for John Anderson, Lithograph created by Louis N. Rosenthal, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Henry Graham Ashmead to C. Henry Kain, June 15, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Henry Graham Ashmead to Prof. C. Henry Kain, April 24, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Sir David Baird, 1st Baronet to A. W. Donald, August 15, 1811 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Joel Barlow to his wife, July 8, 1796 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Joshua Barney to --, June 7, 1791 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- William Barrington, 2nd Viscount to Lord Henry Earl of Lincoln, Warrant for payment, April 24, 1761 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- -- Bayard to Mr. Bowman, November 18, 1778 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- -- Bayard to John Nicholson, May 13, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Karl Bernard, Duke of Saxe-Weimar-Eisenach to Messrs. Leroy, Bayard & Co. [in French], January 6, 1826 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Richard Biddle to C. W. Hasselitz, September 25, 1839 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Soloman Billings, Connecticut militia commission from Jonathan Trumbull, October 17, 1804 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Isaac Blackford to William Croghan Jr., December 26, 1827 and Jan. 26, 1828 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- J. C. Blackford to William Cochran, September 4, 1821 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- John Blackwell to William Penn, November 20, 1688 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- John Blackwell, Account of salary for William Penn, May 15, 1690 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Thomas Bladen to Gentlemen of the Upper House of Assembly (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Lord William Blair to John Covode, August 14, 1864 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- William Blakeley to John Covode, October 28, 1867 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Gabriel Bolong, Deposition, October 17, 1795 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Charles Lucien Jules Laurent Bonaparte to Edward Prince, December 26, 1849 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Jerome Bonaparte to -- [in French], August 27, 1851 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- John J. Born, Affidavit, August 16, 1817 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Bouquet Papers, Handwritten copies of papers held by the British Museum commissioned by William M. Darlington, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Henry Bouquet to John Penn, August 16, 1764 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Henry Bouquet, Certificate of discharge from regiment for John O' Neil, May 2, 1765 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Abner Boyd, Articles of agreement, March 29, 1828 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Abner Boyd to William Croghan Jr., October 3, 1829 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Edward Braddock, Great Britain army indenture for arms, October 12, 1745 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Edward Braddock, Will [copy], November 25, 1754 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Edward Braddock to --, April 15, 1755 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Edward Braddock to Governor Morris, May 4, 1755 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- John Bradstreet to Sir William Johnson, January 12, 1763 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- John Bradstreet to Sir William Johnson, August 10, 1769 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- John Brady, agent for Michael McKewan, Notice of money due Robert Cochran, October 24, 1801 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Joseph Brant to --, December 23, 1794 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Joseph Brant to Israel Chapin, May 13, 1796 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Alexander Scott Bullitt to Henry Lee, March 2, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Ralph Burton to Sir William Johnson, August 16, 1765 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Maria Smith Butler to Samuel Smith, November 2, 1793 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Richard Butler to James Wilson, August 23, 1775 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Richard Butler to Benjamin Lincoln, May 24, 1777 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Richard Butler to Thomas Mifflin, April 1, 1789 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Richard Butler, Receipt signed by John Trumbull, June 20, 1790 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Richard Butler to John Davidson, April 28, 1791 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- William Butler, Continental army report signed by Butler, April 10, 1777 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- William Butler to Board of War, May 1, 1777 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- William Butler to Your Excellency, April 26, 1786 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- William Butler to His Excellency the President and Supreme Executive Council of the State of Pennsylvania, June 2, 1788 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- William Butler to David Reddick, September 14, 1788 (Box 1, Folder 62)
- John Campbell, 4th Earl of Loudoun, Power of Attorney to William Wilkinson, May 17, 1744 (Box 1, Folder 63)
- John Campbell to [Baynton, Wharton & Morgan], November 17, 1767 (Box 1, Folder 64)
- John Campbell to Messrs. Baynton, Wharton & Morgan, December 31, 1767 and January 6, 1768 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- John Campbell to Edward Hand, July 1, 1777 (Box 1, Folder 66)
- Robert Campbell, Partial receipt, October 19, 1785 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- Robert Campbell, Warrant and survey documents, October 17, 1785, November 22, 1833, September 20, 1836, and July 11, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 68)
- Christopher Carleton and Jacob Jordan, Certification of pay, September 13, 1780 (Box 1, Folder 69)
- Sir Guy Carleton, Memoranda relating to pay, undated (Box 1, Folder 70)
- Sir Guy Carleton to -- Rumsey, September 24, 1774 (Box 1, Folder 71)
- Sir Guy Carleton, List of his secretary and aids de camp, November 2, 1782 (Box 1, Folder 72)
- Sir Guy Carleton, 1st Baron Dorchester Account of Lord Dorchester, aids de Camp, and secretary pay, ca. 1787 (Box 1, Folder 73)
- Charles Carroll to Louis McLane, June 19, 1829 (Box 1, Folder 74)
- William Carruthers, Jr., Deposition, March 12, 1768 (Box 1, Folder 75)
- Henry Sweitzer Chalfant to John Covode,November 21, 1860 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Thomas Chambers, Indenture, April 12, 1786 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Benjamin Chew to Honored Sir, July 15, 1751 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Benjamin Chew to Thomas Penn, November 14, 1763 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Benjamin Chew to Joseph Thomas, May 21, 1798 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- -- Christie to Matthew Leslie, March 25, 1768 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- George Rogers Clark to James O'Hara, April 6, 1787 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- George Rogers Clark to James O'Hara, August 25, 1787 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Henry Clay to Major James Fairlie, February 7, 1828 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Henry Clay to Messr. Rapp, April 24, 1829 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Dewitt Clinton to Sachems, Chiefs and Warriors of the Seneca, February 9, 1820 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Sir Henry Clinton to --, October 8, 1755 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- David Cochran to William Croghan Jr., October 12, 1821 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Peter Collinson to Thomas Penn, April 16, 1761 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Committee on Foreign and Domestic Correspondence, Pittsburgh Sanitary Fair Catalogue of autographic letters, autographs, and photographs to be auctioned, June 16, 1864 [typed copy] (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Continental Army, Return of troops 11th Virginia Regiment by Christian Febiger, May 3, 1777 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Continental Army, Report of the main and different guards by Josiah Harmar, May 12, 1777 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Continental Army, Report of the guards by William Heth, May 15, 1777 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Edward Cook to Edward Hand, May 4, 1778 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Edward Cook to Edward Hand, received May 6, 1778 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Gilbert Cope, Ancestral Chart, ca. 1879 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- John Singleton Copley, Baron of Lyndhurst, to --, November 28, 1834 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Lord Charles Cornwallis, 1st Marquis to Sir Charles Burbury, December 12, 1800 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- George H. Covode to John Covode, November 22, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Howard [Covode] to John [Covode], January 30, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- John Covode, Military commission admittance card, May 20, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Neville B. Craig to Edward D. Ingraham, August 3, 1853 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- William Crawford and John Gibson to Archibald Lochry, June 20, 1778 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- William Crawford to Archibald Lochry, September 15, 1778 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Thomas Cresap, Sr., Declaration and attachment signed by William Trent III, December 10, 1753 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Charles Croghan to William Croghan Jr., undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Charles Croghan to William Croghan Jr., undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
- George Croghan, Power of Attorney to Peter Tostee, August 5, 1747 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- George Croghan, Permit for John Bard, May 1, 1762 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- George Croghan to James Harris, July 26, 1762 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- George Croghan to John Jennings, June 1, 1767 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- George Croghan to W. Barnard, ca. 1770 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- George Croghan to Alexander McKee, January 10, 1770 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- George Croghan to Major Funda, May 3, 1770 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- George Croghan to Major Funda, May 19, 1770 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- George Croghan to Barnard Gratz, February 15, 1773 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- George Croghan to Michael Gratz, April 3, 1780 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- George Croghan to Lucy Croghan, July 19, 1829 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- George Croghan Captain White Eyes in Account with George Croghan, 1773 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Mary Croghan to William Croghan Jr., January 23, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Mary Croghan Schenley to Francis Torrance, February 26, 1876 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Mary Croghan Schenley to William Croghan Jr., September 3, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Mary Croghan Schenley to William Croghan Jr. (Box 2, Folder 48)
- William Croghan and George Rogers Clark et al., Indenture with Illinois Land Commission, August 31, 1789 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- William Croghan, Land warrant with later note, September 13, 1797 and April 9, 1813 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- William Croghan Jr., Bill of sale for four Negroes, October 1, 1826 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- William Croghan Jr. to Frederick Rapp Jr., January 8, 1831 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Mrs. Croghan, Account from December 11 to March 31, undated (Box 2, Folder 53)
- Thomas Dagsworthy to Caesar Rodney, September 24, 1777 (Box 2, Folder 54)
- J. Davidson, Andrew Potts' monthly university notice, June 1, 1794 (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Henry Delafield to William Croghan Jr., February 2, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 56)
- Henry Delafield to William Croghan Jr., February 8, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 57)
- Delaware (Colony), Order of Appropriation [duplicate], March 27, 1758 (Box 2, Folder 58)
- William Denny to Conrad Weiser, April 23, 1757 (Box 2, Folder 59)
- William Denny to James Abercrombie, Letter with petition by John Martin, April 7, 1758 (Box 2, Folder 60)
- William Denny to Jacob Shoemaker, Pennsylvania Land patent, September 8, 1758 (Box 2, Folder 61)
- Robert Dinwiddie to Board of Trade, Handwritten copies of papers held by the British Museum commissioned by William M. Darlington, November 17, 1753 (Box 2, Folder 62)
- Robert Dinwiddie to Governor James DeLancey, January 14, 1755 (Box 2, Folder 63)
- Robert Dinwiddie to Governor Robert Hunter Morris, February 21, 1756 (Box 2, Folder 64)
- Robert Dinwiddie to Governor Horatio Sharpe, August 25, 1753 (Box 2, Folder 65)
- Robert Dinwiddie to Governor Horatio Sharpe, October 7, 1754 (Box 2, Folder 66)
- Robert Dinwiddie to Governor Morris, February 14, 1755 (Box 2, Folder 67)
- Arthur Dobbs to Governor Robert Hunter Morris, March 31, 1755 (Box 2, Folder 68)
- Lyman C. Draper to Isaac Craig, September 23, 1881 (Box 2, Folder 69)
- William Dunning, Indenture, October 17, 1791 (Box 2, Folder 70)
- Pierre-Etienne Du Ponceau [signed Peter Du Ponceau], Affidavit, November 25, 1791 (Box 2, Folder 71)
- Ange Duquesne de Manneville, Marquis Duquesne Document [in French], October 2, 1753 (Box 2, Folder 72)
- George Eager, Survey [duplicate], February 9, 1786 (Box 2, Folder 73)
- Earl of Egremont to Lieutenant Governor of Pennsylvania [duplicate], November 27, 1762 (Box 2, Folder 74)
- Earl of Egremont to Deputy Governor of Pennsylvania, February 18, 1763 (Box 2, Folder 75)
- Nathaniel Ellmaker to John Covode, December 4, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 76)
- Richard Elvans et al. Indenture to George W. Haller, February 17, 1829 (Box 2, Folder 77)
- John Ettwein to --, May 5, 1788 (Box 2, Folder 78)
- J. Ewing to Archibald Lochry, August 8, 1777 (Box 2, Folder 79)
- James Ewing Survey [duplicate], May 27, 1785 (Box 2, Folder 80)
- James Ewing, Land patent [duplicate], April 16, 1788 (Box 2, Folder 81)
- Bryan Fairfax to Mrs. Cabot, June 4, 1757 (Box 2, Folder 82)
- Christian Febiger to John Nicholson, March 1790 (Box 2, Folder 83)
- Christian Febiger to John Nicholson, December 17, 1791 (Box 2, Folder 84)
- Christian Febiger to Cashier of the Bank of Pennsylvania, ca. 1794 (Box 2, Folder 85)
- Christian Febiger to John Nicholson, January 7, 1794 (Box 2, Folder 86)
- Robert Edward Fell to Benjamin Chew, February 20, 1772 (Box 2, Folder 87)
- William Findley to John Nicholson,August, 3, 1793 (Box 2, Folder 88)
- William Floyd to George Redington, October 30, 1835 (Box 2, Folder 89)
- Eleanor Forman, Agreement with undated handwritten transcript, November 10, 1698 (Box 2, Folder 90)
- Meeting at Fort Pitt, July 6, 1776 (Box 2, Folder 91)
- Josiah Foster to Enoch Evans, February 25, 1805 (Box 2, Folder 92)
- John Foutch to Soloman Fair, Deed, December 9, 1835 (Box 2, Folder 93)
- Samuel Foutch to Solomon Fair, Deed, December 15, 1835 (Box 2, Folder 94)
- A. Fowler and William Amberson to William Moore, February 10, 1782 (Box 2, Folder 95)
- France, National Convention Extrait du registre des aretes [in French], May 12, 1795 (Box 2, Folder 96)
- Benjamin Franklin to Rev. Mr. Ewing, April 4, 1783 (Box 2, Folder 97)
- William Franklin to Elizabeth "Betsy" Graeme, May 23, 1757 (Box 2, Folder 98)
- Robert Fulton to James Madison, July 8, 1813 (Box 2, Folder 99)
- Thomas Gage to John Bradstreet,June 10, 1765 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Thomas Gage to Sir William Johnson, July 25, 1765 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Thomas Gage, Return of a detachment of the 42nd Regiment, June 15, 1766 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Thomas Gage to Sir William Johnson, October 13, 1766 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Thomas Gage to Sir William Johnson, October 4, 1769 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Thomas Gage to Sir William Johnson, July 28, 1772 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Edmund Gaines Pendleton to Judge Harry Toulmin, Extract of May 18, 1897 letter, June 22, 1807 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Albert Gallatin to Edward Carrington, May 30, 1804 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Albert Gallatin to Erastus Granger, July 29, 1807 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Albert Gallatin to --, September 11, 1816 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Albert Gallatin to Mr. Skinnor [two notes pasted down], [December 12, 1810] and July 21, 1827 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Governor John White Geary to John Covode, Signed resolution, March 9, 1868 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- John Gebhart to Robert Peter, Deed, February 27, 1783 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- King George III and Montagu Dunk, George 2nd Earl of Halifax, to James GranMarch 22, 1764 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- King George III, Pardon for Samuel Russell, January 9, 1798 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- George Gibson to John Nicholson, April 30, 1787 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- John Gibson to Edward Hand, August 1, 1777 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- John Gibson, Receipt, October 1, 1778 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- John Gibson to Thomas Mifflin, October 5, 1793 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- John Gibson to Thomas Mifflin, July 18, 1794 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Gist Family Tree, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Mordecai Gist to John Dorsey [Fine Watermark], September 1, 1776 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Henry Gladwin to [Sir William Johnson], November 16, 1762 (Box 3, Folder 23)